Dhruvin Patel, Hardware Support Technician Candidate

Tel: (204)294-4449

Email: pdhruvin221@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/dhruvinpatel7337

Computer Engineer with 2+ years of experience in the IT industry and end-user support. Extrovert with 3+ years of overall experience with the excellent troubleshooting technique. Project Management Professional with detail-oriented organizing skills who documented, facilitated, and analyzed process workflows, as well as developed system structure in collaboration with multidisciplinary stakeholders to understand the process improvements

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Led network installation encompassing 850 workstations, 35 printers, and 4 communication rooms with supporting infrastructure. The move was accomplished within 6 weeks.
- Managed development teams with the development of PHP and SQL2005 web properties. Saved costs by choosing a new provider of the data system.
- As a final year project during my bachelor's degree, I developed a client server-based communication system which was integrated by a software consultant.

WORK EXPERIENCE

User Support Technician

2016 - 2019

Add-On Computers, Gujarat, India

- Efficient at installing operating systems like Windows, Mac OS, Chrome OS, and all kinds of operating devices. Having sufficient experience working with Google Suite, Google Admin, and device management, cloud-based software.
- Configuring accounts on employee workstations, deploying computer hardware to End Users.
- Working knowledge of Active Directory and Jira.
- Working with JAMF to deploy Mac OS computers, working with Azure and Intune to deploy policies and software on Windows computers.
- Determined users' needs and desires by specifying the research needed to obtain market information.
- Analyzed inventory turnover and product availability by reviewing and adjusting inventory levels and schedules.
- Led and supervised the IT support team responsible for the whole campus.
- Prepared monthly reports and gave quarterly presentations to superiors as per the surveys made from the monthly business.

PHP Developer / Product Management (Freelance)

2017 - 2018

Lotus Digital Consultants, Gujarat, India

- Collaborated closely with development and business team in agile scrum methodologies and administered daily stand up scrum meetings.
- Recommended the nature and scope of present and future product lines by reviewing product specifications and requirements.
- Participated in user story estimation and complexity calculation process with collaborating development team to ensure the effectiveness of the scrum

Dhruvin Patel, Hardware Support Technician Candidate

Tel: (204)294-4449

Email: pdhruvin221@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/dhruvinpatel7337

- Created new forms to collect and validate data from the user in HTML5 and JavaScript, which improved completion rate by 55%.
- Managed hardware and software for the eCommerce department in 2017-2018 (including budgets, purchasing/inventory) and assisted with the deployment of assets, reducing costs by \$33,000.
- Managed a staff of six programmers and designers on business client Internet/e-commerce web sites.
- Delivered end results by fulfilling the company's yearly goals within a timeline.
- Assessed market competition by comparing the company's product to competitors' products.

Global Operations Specialist

2020 - Present

SkipTheDishes, Winnipeg

- As an operations team member, advised colleagues when they were stuck in a situation. Gave a satisfying solution to customers considering Empathy as the main element.
- Provided excellent customer service by engaging with clients and delivering outstanding services with proactive communication skills and emotional intelligence. Identified opportunities for customers to provide the best advice as well as the solution to their problem.
- Always took the responsibility of solving client issues and prevent them from occurring by using my strong interpersonal and active listening skills.
- Proven self-motivated and flexible, prioritized customers first with success hands-on.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATION

React.js	Present
ComIT	
Post-Graduate Diploma in Project Management	2019 - 2020
University of Winnipeg, Winnipeg, MB	
Certificate in Management	2019 - 2020
Canadian Institute of Management	
Bachelor's in Information & Technology Engineering Gujarat Technological University, Gujarat, India.	2012 - 2016

Dhruvin Patel, Hardware Support Technician Candidate

Tel: (204)294-4449

Email: pdhruvin221@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/dhruvinpatel7337

VOLUNTEER AND COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT:

PMI Manitoba Chapter 2019 - Present Social Media Promotion 2011 - Present

Safayar Ceramics, PVT, LTD, India

Kitchen assistant 2019 - Present

Siloam Mission, Winnipeg

REFERENCES AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST